hey guys so let's simplify this
expression it's kind of fun it's got a
bunch of three five sevens in it let's
see what happens when we simplify it so
let's start with inside the parentheses
357 over 357 is equal to one and then
one plus three plus five plus seven is
equal to 16. 3 times 5 times 7 is 105.
take the square root of 16 to the 105.
anytime we take a square root with an
exponent you can just divide that
exponent by two but 105 is an odd number
I want to try to keep things clean so
there is a way for us to make this even
we can rewrite the 16 inside the
parentheses is 4 squared and then this 2
is going to multiply by the 105 to give
us 4 to the 210 power now this 210 is
even so when I take the square root of
it it's just going to divide this by 2
which gives me 105. I want to take the
7th root I'm just going to divide this
exponent by 7 which gives me 4 to the
power of 15. then when I take the fifth
root I'm going to divide this 15 by 5 to
give me 4 cubed and then when I take the
cube root that's going to cancel with
the cube to give me just 4. and 7 times
4 is 28 28 times 5 is 140 3 times 140 is
420. nice so this simplifies to 420. how
exciting